Wenting Zhang

Kobe, Hyogo, Japan

Affiliation: Kobe University, 2-1 Rokkodai-cho Nada, Kobe, Hyogo 657-8501, Japan

Website: wentingzhang.org | Google Scholar

Email: choubunntei@yahoo.co.jp | zhangwenting.kobe@gmail.com



SUMMARY

I am currently a Ph.D. candidate at the Department of Economics at Kobe University, supervised by Professor Shigeyuki Hamori. The main direction of my research is the time series analysis of financial market crises. I specialize in using econometric models such as ARMA-GARCH models, DCC-GARCH models, TVP-VAR models, Data mining techniques, and machine learning models such as XGboost, Random Forest. As of 2023, I have published five papers in major SSCI and SCIE journals and authored one book. One of my first-author papers is listed as highly cited paper over 180 times by Google Scholar.

RESEARCH INTEREST

Time series analysis, Machine learning, Data analysis

EDUCATION

Kobe University

Ph.D. candidate of Science in Economics

Kobe University

Master of Science in Economics

China Three Gorges University

Bachelor of Arts in Japanese language

Rokkodai-cho Nada, Kobe, Hyogo, Japan Apr 2021 –

Rokkodai-cho Nada, Kobe, Hyogo, Japan Apr 2019 – Mar 2021

> Yichang City, Hubei Province, China Sep 2014 – Jun 2018

PUBLICATIONS

- Papers

- [1] **Zhang, W.**, He, X., & Hamori, S. (2022). Volatility spillover and investment strategies among sustainability-related financial indexes: Evidence from the DCC-GARCH-based dynamic connectedness and DCC-GARCH t-copula approach. *International Review of Financial Analysis*, 83, 102223. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.irfa.2022.102223
- [2] **Zhang, W.**, & Hamori, S. (2021). THE CONNECTEDNESS BETWEEN THE SENTIMENT INDEX AND STOCK RETURN VOLATIL-ITY UNDER COVID-19: A TIME-VARYING PARAMETER VECTOR AUTOREGRESSION APPROACH. *The Singapore Economic Review,* 1–32. https://doi.org/10.1142/s0217590822500023
- [3] **Zhang, W.**, & Hamori, S. (2021). Crude oil market and stock markets during the COVID-19 pandemic: Evidence from the US, Japan, and Germany. *International Review of Financial Analysis*, 74, 101702. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.irfa.2021.101702
- [4] **Zhang, W.**, & Hamori, S. (2020). Do Machine Learning Techniques and Dynamic Methods Help Forecast US Natural Gas Crises? *Energies*, *13*(9), 2371. https://doi.org/10.3390/en13092371
- [5] **Zhang, W.**, He, X., Nakajima, T., & Hamori, S. (2020). How Does the Spillover among Natural Gas, Crude Oil, and Electricity Utility Stocks Change over Time? Evidence from North America and Europe. *Energies, 13(3)*, 727. https://doi.org/10.3390/en13030727

- Books

[1] Tadahiro Nakajima, Shigeyuki Hamori, Xie He, Guizhou Liu, **Wenting Zhang**, Yulian Zhang, & Tiantian Liu. (2021). *ESG investment in the global economy*. Springer. ISBN: 978-981-16-2990-7

EXPERIENCE

May. 2020-Feb. 2021	Research Assistant, Graduate School of Economics, Kobe University
Oct. 2021-Dec. 2021	Research Assistant, Graduate School of Economics, Kobe University
Apr. 2022-Aug. 2022	Teaching Assistant, Graduate School of Economics, Kobe University
Jan. 2023-Feb. 2023	Research Assistant, Center for Mathematical Data Science, Kobe University
Apr. 2023-Aug. 2023	Teaching Assistant, Graduate School of Economics, Kobe University
Apr. 2023-	Membership, Western Economic Association International

SKILLS

Languages : English, Japanese

Programming : R, python

AWARDS AND HONORS

Mar. 2020 Rokkodai Research Excellence Award, Kobe University
Mar. 2021 Rokkodai Research Excellence Award, Kobe University
Mar. 2023 Rokkodai Research Excellence Award, Kobe University
Apr. 2021-Mar. 2022 Scholarship Student, Otsuka Toshimi Scholarship Foundation
Apr. 2022-Mar. 2023 Scholarship Student, Otsuka Toshimi Scholarship Foundation